#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ mikebloomberg (LinkedIn) www.mikebloomberg.com (Other) www.bloomberg.org (Other) www.bloomberg.com (Other)

## Mike Bloomberg

Entrepreneur, philanthropist, and three-term mayor of New York City. New York

#### Summary

Mike Bloomberg is an entrepreneur and philanthropist who served three terms as Mayor of the City of New York.

Born in Boston on February 14, 1942 and raised in a middle class home in Medford, Massachusetts, Michael Bloomberg attended Johns Hopkins University, where he paid his tuition by taking out loans and working as a parking lot attendant. After college, he attended Harvard Business School and in 1966 was hired by a Wall Street firm, Salomon Brothers, for an entry-level job.

Bloomberg quickly rose through the ranks at Salomon, overseeing equity trading and sales before heading up the firm's information systems. When Salomon was acquired in 1981, he was let go from the firm. With a vision of an information technology company that would bring transparency and efficiency to the buying and selling of financial securities, he launched a small startup in a one room office. Today, Bloomberg LP is a global company that has more than 15,000 employees and offices in 73 countries around the world.

During his tenure as mayor, from 2002 through 2013, Bloomberg brought his innovation-driven approach to city government. He turned around a broken public school system by raising standards and holding schools accountable for success. He spurred economic growth and job creation by revitalizing old industrial areas, spurring entrepreneurship, supporting small businesses, and strengthening key industries.

His passion for public health led to ambitious new strategies that became national models, including a ban on smoking in all indoor workplaces, as well as at parks and beaches.

Upon leaving City Hall, Michael Bloomberg returned to the company he founded, Bloomberg LP, while also devoting more time to philanthropy, which has been a top priority for him throughout his career.

Today, Bloomberg Philanthropies (founded in 2006) employs a unique data-driven approach to global change that grows out of his experiences as an entrepreneur and mayor.

### Experience

Bloomberg LP Founder and CEO 2014 - Present (6 years)

Bloomberg, the global business and financial information and news leader, gives influential decision makers a critical edge by connecting them to a dynamic network of information, people and ideas. The company's strength – delivering data, news and analytics through innovative technology, quickly and accurately – is at the core of the Bloomberg Terminal. Bloomberg's enterprise solutions build on the company's core strength: leveraging technology to allow customers to access, integrate, distribute and manage data and information across organizations more efficiently and effectively.

#### Bloomberg Philanthropies Founder 2006 - Present (14 years)

Bloomberg Philanthropies employs a unique data-driven approach to global change that grows out of Mike Bloomberg's experiences as an entrepreneur and mayor. Bloomberg Philanthropies focuses on five key areas for creating lasting change: public health, environment, education, government innovation, and arts & culture. These five areas encompass the issues Bloomberg and his team are most passionate about, and where they believe the greatest good can be achieved.

# United Nations 5 years 11 months

Special Envoy for Climate Action March 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 9 months)

As the Secretary-General's Special Envoy for Climate Action, Mike Bloomberg supports the action of global cities, states and regions, businesses and investors, and civil society to accelerate progress on climate change.

Special Envoy for Cities and Climate Change to the Secretary-General January 2014 - March 2018 (4 years 3 months)

As Special Envoy for Cities and Climate Change, Mike Bloomberg assisted the Secretary-General in his consultations with mayors and related key stakeholders to drive cities to take action on climate change.

World Health Organization Global Ambassador for Noncommunicable Diseases August 2016 - November 2019 (3 years 4 months)

In this role, Mike Bloomberg works with national and local political leaders around the globe to highlight the burden of noncommunicable diseases like heart disease and cancer, and injuries such as those from road traffic accidents. Through efforts like the Partnership for Healthy Cities, he helps mobilize those leaders, donors and the private sector to fight noncommunicable diseases and save lives.

City of New York Mayor of New York City January 2002 - December 2013 (12 years)

In 2001, Mike Bloomberg was elected the 108th Mayor of the City of New York, and he was re-elected in 2005 and 2009. While in office, he cut crime by more than 30 percent and created jobs by attracting new investment and supporting small business growth. He implemented ambitious public health strategies, including a ban on smoking in restaurants and bars. Through these efforts, the Mayor helped increased the average life expectancy of residents in New York City by 3 years. His education reforms drove graduation rates up more than 40 percent. The Mayor's economic policies helped New York avoid the level of job losses that many other cities experienced during the national recession.

Bloomberg LP Founder 1981 - 2001 (20 years)

Bloomberg, the global business and financial information and news leader, gives influential decision makers a critical edge by connecting them to a dynamic network of information, people and ideas. The company's strength – delivering data, news and analytics through innovative technology, quickly and accurately – is at the core of the Bloomberg Professional service, which provides real time financial information to more than 315,000 subscribers globally. Bloomberg's enterprise solutions build on the company's core strength, leveraging technology to allow customers to access, integrate,

distribute and manage data and information across organizations more efficiently and effectively. Through Bloomberg Law, Bloomberg Government, Bloomberg New Energy Finance and Bloomberg BNA, the company provides data, news and analytics to decision makers in industries beyond finance. And Bloomberg News, delivered through the Bloomberg Professional service, television, radio, mobile, the Internet and two magazines, Bloomberg Businessweek and Bloomberg Markets, covers the world with more than 2,430 news and multimedia professionals at 146 bureaus in 72 countries. Headquartered in New York, Bloomberg employs more than 15,000 people in 192 locations around the world.

Salomon Brothers
General Partner
June 1966 - September 1981 (15 years 4 months)

#### Education

Harvard Business School MBA · (1964 - 1966)

The Johns Hopkins University

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering · (1960 - 1964)